The Hudson River Environmental Society Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Hudson River Environmental Society Collection
1963 - 2005
NPkMC-223-071
26 linear feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Hudson River Environmental Society Collection documents the research, actions, and legal cases involving environmental issues surrounding the Hudson River Valley. Various interests include Storm King Mountain, Con Edison’s Cornwall Pumps, Indian Point, Dredging, Transportation, Danskammer, and many others. The collection also contains communication and records of cooperation with other environmental groups such as Scenic Hudson and the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council.
Related Collections
Grim Collection
Hudson River Environmental Society Library
Hudson River Valley Greenway Counsil Collection
Hudson River GREEN Collection
Saunders Papers
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Administrative History Collection
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Collection
Seymour Papers
Collection Overview
The Hudson River Environmental Society Collection contains materials and documents pertaining to the history and accomplishments of the Hudson River Environmental Society. Its contents consist of correspondence, subject files, scientific studies, legal papers, printed materials, and photographs.
The Hudson River Environmental Society Collection was donated to the Marist College Library by the Hudson River Environmental Society in 2003.
Historical Note
The Hudson River Environmental Society (HRES), a nonprofit organization, was founded in 1970 to research and make available that research of the Hudson River environment and related costal areas, as well as providing communication and cooperation among researchers. While still managing to be objective, HRES provides valuable information on forces that affect the environment surrounding the Hudson River. Studies include topics ranging from PCBs, Acid Rain, Dredging, the Hudson River Fisheries, State Environmental Quality, Cultural Resources, Scenic and Historic Area Preservation, Toxic and Hazardous Waste, and others. Membership in the society includes corporate members, individuals from academic and research institutions, consulting firms, government agencies, organizations concerned with environmental matters in the Hudson Valley, and interested citizens. The Society’s best known activities include conferences and workshops on a variety of environmental issues concerning the Hudson River Valley, which attract participants from the region as well as neighboring states.
No Restrictions
- 1. Correspondence, Box 1; 1; 1.33 linear feet 1 - 2 1 - 34
  Communication between members of the Hudson River Environmental Society, the community, and various organizations and companies.
  By subject
  - Personal Correspondence, 1; Box 1
    - DEC Correspondence: 1973-1977, 1 (Box 1)
    - DEC Correspondence: 1978-1982, 2 (Box 1)
    - DEC Correspondence: Proposed Classifications and Standards of Quality and Purity, 3 (Box 1)
    - DOI/FWS Correspondence June 1975 - III A, 4 (Box 1)
    - Albert G. Hall, 5 (Box 1)
    - Con. Ed. Consultant, 6 (Box 1)
    - EPA, 7 (Box 1)
    - EPA (legal size), 8 (Box 1)
    - Harry G. Woodbury, 9 (Box 1)
    - Dr. Kenneth Marcellus, 10 (Box 1)
    - Letter from Senator Ribicoff to Dr. Ray, 11 (Box 1)
    - Michael F. Stoll, 1976-1977, 12 (Box 1)
    - Michael F. Stoll, 1978, 13 (Box 1)
    - Michael F. Stoll, 1979-1983, 14 (Box 1)
    - Michael F. Stoll, Not Dated, 15 (Box 1)
    - NJ DEP, 16 (Box 1)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 17 (Box 1)
    - Paul Hamilton, 18 (Box 1)
    - Congressman Richard Ottinger, 19 (Box 1)
    - Scenic Hudson 1989-1990, 20 (Box 1)
    - Speech - Wilkens, Barbara J., 21 (Box 1)
    - Staff Biologist, 1976-1981, 22 (Box 1)
    - Striped Bass Funding, Inc., 23 (Box 1)
    - Stoll’s Communication & Notes, 1974-06/1976, 24 (Box 1)
    - Stoll’s Communication & Notes, 07/1976-12/1976, 26 (Box 1)
    - Stoll’s Communication & Notes, 01/1977-06/1977, 26 (Box 1)
    - Stoll’s Communication & Notes, 07/1977-1979, 27 (Box 1)
    - Stoll’s Communication & Notes, Not Dated, 28 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 2; Box 2
    - General Correspondence: 1973-1977, 29 (Box 2)
    - General Correspondence: 1978, 30 (Box 2)
    - General Correspondence: 1979, 31 (Box 2)
    - General Correspondence: 1980-1982, 32 (Box 2)
    - General Correspondence: Not Dated, 33 (Box 2)
    - Phone Records, 1978-1982, 34 (Box 2)
- 2. Meetings, 2; 0.67 linear feet 2 35 - 50
  Memos, announcements, notes, agendas, and minutes of meetings.
  By subject, chronologically
  - Meetings, Box 2; 2
    Meetings
    - American Shad Workshop Dec. 14-16, 1976, 35 (Box 2)
    - Notifications, 1976-1977, 36 (Box 2)
    - Notifications, 1978-1979, 37 (Box 2)
    - Notifications, 1980-1981, 38 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1969-1975, 39 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1976, 40 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1977, 41 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1978, 42 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1979, 43 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1980-1981, 44 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, Not Dated, 45 (Box 2)
    - Policy Committee, 46 (Box 2)
    - Technical Committee, 1969-1975, 47 (Box 2)
    - Technical Committee, 1976-1978, 48 (Box 2)
    - Technical Committee, 1979-1980, 49 (Box 2)
    - Technical Committee, Not Dated, 50 (Box 2)
- 3. Subject Files, 3; 6 linear feet 3 - 8 51 - 330
  Files of environmental concern researched and referenced by HRES.
  - Add Locks, Box 3; 3.1
    Documents, studies, and correspondence relating to adding locks to rivers
    Alphabetically
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: A Benthos, 51 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: B Fish, 52 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: C Birds, 53 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: D Mammals, 54 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: E Amphibians & Reptiles, 55 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Section: F Vegetation, 56 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Appendix, 57 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Rocks, 58 (Box 3)
    - Biological Survey - St. Lawrence R., Unusable Originals, 59 (Box 3)
    - Clippings (Copies), 60 (Box 3)
    - Clippings 1979, 61 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1980 (1), 62 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1980 (2), 63 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1980 (3), 64 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1981 (1), 65 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1981 (2), 66 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1982 (1), 67 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1982 (2), 68 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Sections 1-6, 69 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix A: Natural Environment, 70 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix B: Human Environment, 71 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix C: Capacity, 72 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix D: Maximum Vessel Size Study, 73 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix F: Public Concerns, 74 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendix G: Coordination and Pertinent Correspondence, 75 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study, Appendixes H-J, 76 (Box 3)
    - Impacts on Levels and Flows, 77 (Box 3)
    - International Lake Erie Regulation Study, 78 (Box 3)
    - Organic Analysis of Benthos, 79 (Box 3)
    - Proposal (& Notes), 80 (Box 3)
    - Qualitative Assessment of Potential Recreational Boating Impacts..., 81 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations, 82 (Box 3)
    - Reconciliation Between Levels and Flows, 83 (Box 3)
  - Black Rock Forest, 3.2
    Files related to the Black Rock Forest
    - Black Rock Forest, 84 (Box 3)
  - Cornwall Project, 3.3
    Legal documents, studies, and correspondence related to the Cornwall Project
    - Affidavit, 85 (Box 4)
    - Alden Study, 86 (Box 4)
    - Annual Report 1973, 87 (Box 4)
    - Answer to Dept. of Interior to Intervenors’ Cross-Motions to Vacate or Reopen the Cornwall License, 88 (Box 4)
    - Cornwall Application for Rehearing, 89 (Box 4)
    - Calculation Procedures, Texas Instruments, 90 (Box 4)
    - Catch Summary Data June-July 1973, 91 (Box 4)
    - Con Ed. Answer to Motions to Revoke the License or to Reopen the Licensing Proceeding, 92 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 93 (Box 4)
    - Cost Estimates, 94 (Box 4)
    - Dye-Dispersion Study, 95 (Box 4)
    - Evaluation of Potential Damage to Fish, 96 (Box 4)
    - Evaluation of Testimony, 97 (Box 4)
    - Gear Evaluation Study 1974, 98 (Box 4)
    - Hudson River Biological Study, 99 (Box 4)
    - Hudson River Fisheries Investigations 1965-1968, 100 (Box 4)
    - Hudson River Power Plant Coordinator Position, 101 (Box 4)
    - Hydroelectric Model Study Progress Report 1973, 102 (Box 4)
    - Ichthyoplankton River Survey Project, 103 (Box 4)
    - Impact Report 1974, 104 (Box 4)
    - Impact Report 1974 (duplicate), 105 (Box 4)
    - Impact Report (incomplete), 106 (Box 4)
    - Influence of the Proposed Cornwall... Project... Sections 1-2, 107 (Box 4)
    - Influence of the Proposed Cornwall... Project... Sections 3-5, 108 (Box 4)
    - Influence of the Proposed Cornwall... Project... Section 6 - Appendix D, 109 (Box 4)
    - Interrogatories - Austin, Garrett E., 110 (Box 4)
    - Interrogatories - Azzaro, Richard A., 111 (Box 4)
    - Memorandum Concerning the Contribution of the Hudson River Striped Bass to the Mid-Atlantic Fishery, 112 (Box 4)
    - Model Study 1966, 113 (Box 4)
    - Model Study 1969, 114 (Box 4)
    - Monthly Status Report April 1973, 115 (Box 4)
    - Monthly Status Report May 1973, 116 (Box 4)
    - Petition to Intervene, 117 (Box 4)
    - Physical, Chemical, and Biological Characteristics of the Hudson River, 118 (Box 4)
    - Preliminary Environmental Impact Statement of Proposed Landfill Park..., 119 (Box 4)
    - Preliminary Impact Statement 1973, 120 (Box 4)
    - Preliminary Impact Statement on Proposed Landfill Site, 121 (Box 4)
    - Procedures for the Calculation of 1973..., 122 (Box 4)
    - Response to Additional Information 06/27/1978, 123 (Box 4)
    - Response to Commission’s Order of Jan. 30, 1975 by Con. Edison, 124 (Box 4)
    - Section 8 Entrainment of Striped Bass, 125 (Box 4)
    - Terrestrial Survey in the Vicinity of the Proposed Cornwall Landfill Park, 126 (Box 4)
  - Dredging, 3.4
    Files relating to the dredging in the Hudson River
    - Dredging, 127 (Box 4)
  - Hudson Estuary Fisheries Development Program, 3.5
    Files relating to the Hudson Estuary Fisheries Development Program
    - Hudson Estuary Fisheries Development Program, 128 (Box 4)
  - Hudson River Atlas, 3.6
    Correspondence and proposals concerning Hudson River Atlas
    - Correspondence, 129 (Box 4)
    - Memorandum of Need, 130 (Box 4)
    - Notes, 131 (Box 4)
    - Phone Conversations, 132 (Box 4)
    - Proposal, 133 (Box 4)
    - Proposal for Financial Support, 134 (Box 4)
    - Proposal to Produce Book Series, 135 (Box 4)
  - Hudson River Basin, Box 5; 3.7
    Studies related to the Hudson River Basin
    - Allocation, 136 (Box 5)
    - Anatomy of an Environment Final Study, 137 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 138 (Box 5)
    - Disposition of Dredged Materials, 139 (Box 5)
    - Fish and Wildlife Report, 140 (Box 5)
    - Flood Damage Reduction, 141 (Box 5)
    - Plan of Study, 142 (Box 5)
    - Plan of Study Draft, 143 (Box 5)
    - Plan of Study Preliminary Draft, 144 (Box 5)
    - Plan of Study Preliminary Draft (duplicate), 145 (Box 5)
    - Proposal for Preparing a Subregional Plan: The Highlands Development Project, 146 (Box 5)
    - Recreation, 147 (Box 5)
    - Water and Related Land Resources Study, 1976, 148 (Box 5)
    - Water Supply, 149 (Box 5)
  - Hudson River Level B. Study, Box 5; 3.8
    Legal papers and documents concerning the Hudson River Level B. Study
    - Plan of Study, 150 (Box 5)
    - Proposal, 151 (Box 5)
    - Public Law 92-500: Letter of Concern, 152 (Box 5)
  - Hudson River Lower Basin, Box 5; 3.9
    Minutes and reports concerning the Hudson River Lower Basin
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Meeting Summary, 153 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Mtg. Announcement & Agenda, 154 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Introductory Materials, 155 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Meeting Notes, 156 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Water Resource Management, 157 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Flood Damage Reduction, 158 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Recreation (F & W), 159 (Box 5)
    - Joint Work Group Meetings: Dredging Material Disposal, 160 (Box 5)
    - Pre-drafts of Final Report: Announcements and Notes, 161 (Box 5)
    - Pre-drafts of Final Report: Chapter 2, 162 (Box 5)
    - Pre-drafts of Final Report: Chapter 5, 163 (Box 5)
    - List of Problems and Needs, 164 (Box 5)
  - Hudson River Lower Basin, Box 5; 3.10
    Minutes, clippings, and correspondence from the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council
    - Bear Mountain Public Meeting Minutes 07/12/1989, 165 (Box 5)
    - Bear Mountain Public Meeting Speakers (1), 166 (Box 5)
    - Bear Mountain Public Meeting Speakers (2), 167 (Box 5)
    - Bear Mountain Public Meeting Speakers (3), 168 (Box 5)
    - Catskill Public Hearing Speakers, 169 (Box 5)
    - Catskill Public Meeting, 170 (Box 5)
    - Clippings 10/11/1989, 171 (Box 5)
    - Clippings 10/17/1989, 172 (Box 5)
    - Clippings 11/07/1989, 173 (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 174 (Box 5)
    - Clippings (copies), 175 (Box 5)
    - Comments on Draft Environmental Impact Statement Near Mine, Ancram, 176 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 177 (Box 5)
    - Editorials in Support, 178 (Box 5)
    - Guide to Legislation, 179 (Box 5)
    - (an) Informal Analysis of Activities, 180 (Box 5)
    - Mailings, 181 (Box 5)
    - Maps, 182 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Agenda, 183 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes 06/1994, 184 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes 10/04/1994, 185 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes 06/06/1995, 186 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Notice, 187 (Box 5)
    - Petition Signatures, 188 (Box 5)
    - Presentation of Secretary of State, Gail S. Shaffer, 189 (Box 5)
    - Press Release, 190 (Box 5)
    - Statement - Sampson, David S., 191 (Box 5)
    - Testimony - Hagen, William F., 192 (Box 5)
    - Testimony - Haley, Thomas, 193 (Box 5)
    - Testimony - Keene, Chuck, 194 (Box 5)
    - Testimony - Lopez, Peter, 195 (Box 5)
    - Yonkers Public Hearing, 196 (Box 5)
  - Indian Point, Box 6; 3.11
    Studies, correspondence, and legal papers relating to Indian Point
    - Analysis of Indian Point 2 ALAB Decision, 197 (Box 6)
    - Application for Facility License Amendment... Amendment No. 1, 198 (Box 6)
    - Benefit-Cost Analysis of Alternative Operating Modes for the Period 1973-1977, 199 (Box 6)
    - Benthos Data Display, 04/1977, 200 (Box 6)
    - Brief, 201 (Box 6)
    - Comments on the Draft Detailed Statement on Environmental Considerations... by Luis J. Lefleowitz, 202 (Box 6)
    - Communication with Raytheon Company, 203 (Box 6)
    - Con Edison Response to HRFA Draft Detailed Statement, 204 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Con Edison, 205 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1969, 206 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 01/1970-04/1970, 207 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 05/1970-1974, 208 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Not Dated, 209 (Box 6)
    - Decision, 210 (Box 6)
    - Decision 04/04/1974, 211 (Box 6)
    - Detailed Statement on the Environmental Considerations..., 212 (Box 6)
    - Ecological Studies on the Relation of Indian Point Nuclear Generating Station to the Lower Hudson River, 213 (Box 6)
    - Ecological Study Final Report 1967-1971, 214 (Box 6)
    - Ecological Study of the Hudson River 1969-1970, 215 (Box 6)
    - Ecology Program, Raytheon Company, 216 (Box 6)
    - Environmental Report Supplement No. 1 Dec. 1971, 217 (Box 6)
    - Environmental Report Supplement 10 Nov. 1973, 218 (Box 6)
    - Environmentally Related Reports Since December 1974, 219 (Box 6)
    - Effect of Indian Point Cooling Water Discharge on Hudson River Temperature Distribution, 220 (Box 6)
    - Errata for Influence of Indian Point... on Striped Bass..., 221 (Box 6)
    - Errata for Supplement I Influence of Indian Point... on Striped Bass..., 222 (Box 6)
    - Fact Sheet, 223 (Box 6)
    - Final Facility Description and Safety Analysis Report, 224 (Box 6)
    - Fish Protection, 225 (Box 6)
    - First Progress Report, August 1975, 226 (Box 6)
    - Hydraulic Model Study of Cooling Water Recirculation in Screenwall, 227 (Box 6)
    - Impact of Effects of Multiple Plant Operation on the Conclusions Reached in the Final Environmental Statement..., 228 (Box 6)
    - Initial Submittal, 09/10/1974, 229 (Box 6)
    - Legal Memorandum, 230 (Box 6)
    - List of Testimony Dated 02/05/1973, 231 (Box 6)
    - Meetings, 232 (Box 6)
    - Memorandum Status Report - Fish Impingement Study March-April 1973, 233 (Box 6)
    - Memorandum Status Report - Fish Impingement Study May-June 1973, 234 (Box 6)
    - Memorandum Status Report - Fish Impingement Study July-Aug 1973, 235 (Box 6)
    - Monthly Status Report Jan-Feb Ecological Study 1973, 236 (Box 6)
    - Order 09/21/1973, 237 (Box 6)
    - Position of Fisherman’s Association, 238 (Box 6)
    - Proposed Program of Biological and Engineering Studies..., 239 (Box 6)
    - Ranking of Ichthyoplankton Abundance 1974-1976, 240 (Box 6)
    - Regulatory Staff Submittals Regarding Environmental Issues, 241 (Box 6)
    - Report of Inquiry into Allegations Concerning Operation..., 242 (Box 6)
    - Report of Operations, 243 (Box 6)
    - Revised Generating Costs, 244 (Box 6)
    - Staff’s Position of Thermal Hydraulic Issues, 245 (Box 6)
    - Status Report #7 Fish Impingement, 246 (Box 6)
    - Supplemental Study of Effect of Submerged Discharge... on Temperature Distribution, 247 (Box 6)
    - Supplementary Reports to be Presented to the Advisory Board March 4, 1971, 248 (Box 6)
    - Temperature Distribution, 249 (Box 6)
    - Thermal Effects Report, 250 (Box 6)
    - Transport of Contaminants in the Hudson River, 251 (Box 6)
  - Liberty Park, Box 7; 3.12
    Studies related to the Liberty Park Project
    - Ecological Study 1st Quarterly Report, 252 (Box 7)
    - Ecological Study 3rd Quarterly Report, 253 (Box 7)
    - Survey of Aquatic Organisms, 254 (Box 7)
  - Liberty Park, Box 7; 3.13
    Studies organized by HRES concerning Norrie Point
    - NP 497: Comprehensive Solid Waste Study Summary Report, 255 (Box 7)
    - NP 498: Interim Report on Municipal Solid Waste, 256 (Box 7)
    - NP 533: Applications for Department of the Army Permits for Activities in Waterways, 257 (Box 7)
    - NP 534: Bergen County Toxic Substances Public Participation Task Force, 258 (Box 7)
    - NP 535: Some Small Mammals of Wilsey Valley, 259 (Box 7)
    - NP 536: Mission 5000, 260 (Box 7)
    - NP 537: Classifications and Standards Governing the Quality and Purity of Waters of NYS, 261 (Box 7)
    - NP 538: Proposed Classifications and Standards Governing the Quality and Purity of Waters of NYS, 262 (Box 7)
    - NP 539: Freshwater Wetlands, 263 (Box 7)
    - NP 544: A Report on the Quality of the Waters of the Hudson River, 264 (Box 7)
    - NP 545: The Hudson River Estuary, 265 (Box 7)
    - NP 546: Comparison of Dredge and Core Sampling of River Sediments..., 266 (Box 7)
    - NP 548: Health Physics Aspects of Nuclear Facility Siting, 267 (Box 7)
    - NP 549: Radiocesium and Distribution in Water, Sediment, and Biota in the Hudson, 268 (Box 7)
    - NP 550: Stable Manganese and Mn-54 Distributions in the Physical and Biological Components of the Hudson River Estuary, 269 (Box 7)
    - NP 551: Natural Activity in the Hudson River Estuary Samples..., 270 (Box 7)
    - NP 576: Memorandum on Solid Waste Policy - Tentative Draft, 271 (Box 7)
    - NP 577: Projects in the Upper Hudson, Lower Hudson, and Mohawk River Basins (list), 272 (Box 7)
    - NP 578: Zoning Ordinance 1974, 273 (Box 7)
    - NP 581: Solid Waste Management Law, 274 (Box 7)
    - NP 582: Urban Wildlife Habitat Inventory Map Overlay User Information, 275 (Box 7)
  - Roseton/Danskammer, Box 7; 3.14
    Legal documents and studies concerning Roseton and Danskammer
    - Entrainment Data, 1974, 276 (Box 7)
    - Interrogatories (1), 277 (Box 7)
    - Interrogatories (2), 278 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 279 (Box 7)
    - Studies, 280 (Box 7)
    - Summary of 1975 Ecological Fish Samples Pages 1-100, 281 (Box 7)
    - Summary of 1975 Ecological Fish Samples Pages 101-200, 282 (Box 7)
    - Summary of 1975 Ecological Fish Samples Pages 201-300, 283 (Box 7)
    - Summary of 1975 Ecological Fish Samples Pages 301-400, 284 (Box 7)
    - Summary of 1975 Ecological Fish Samples Pages 401-519, 285 (Box 7)
    - Testimony (1), 286 (Box 7)
    - Testimony (2), 287 (Box 7)
    - Testimony (3), 288 (Box 7)
  - Transportation, Box 8; 3.15
    Studies and plans for repair on various bridges and roadways
    - Cayuga County - Bridge over Hemlock Creek, 289 (Box 8)
    - City of Amsterdam - Florida Ave over Choctannuda Creek, 290 (Box 8)
    - City of Cortland - Madison Street over Dry Creek, 291 (Box 8)
    - City of Fulton - Oneida Street Bridge, 292 (Box 8)
    - Courtland County - Groton Ave Bridge over Otter Creek, 293 (Box 8)
    - Fulton County - Route 29A Gloversville, 294 (Box 8)
    - Greenbridge Road over Middle Branch Moose River, 295 (Box 8)
    - Hamilton County - Mountain Home Road, 296 (Box 8)
    - Lake Onondaga West Shore Development, 297 (Box 8)
    - Livingston County - Bridge over Beards Creek, 298 (Box 8)
    - Madison County - Russell Street over Chittenango Creek, 299 (Box 8)
    - Monroe County - Route 261 Bridge over West Creek, 300 (Box 8)
    - Montgomery County - C.R. 82 over Bowman’s Creek, 301 (Box 8)
    - Oneida County - Bridge over Wood Creek Routes 46 & 49, 302 (Box 8)
    - Oneida County - Fish Creek Landing, 303 (Box 8)
    - Oneida County - Kellogg Road, 304 (Box 8)
    - Seneca County - Sheldrake-East Varick State Highway, 305 (Box 8)
    - Syracuse-Cicero Highway (Route 11) Reconstruction, 306 (Box 8)
    - Town of Bergen - Route 19 Bridge over Black Creek, 307 (Box 8)
    - Town of Brookfield - Bridge on the Skaneateles Turnpike over Beaver Creek, 308 (Box 8)
    - Town of Camillus - Bridge over Conrail, 309 (Box 8)
    - Town of Frankfort Center - Bridge over Ferguson Creek, 310 (Box 8)
    - Village of Manlius, 311 (Box 8)
    - Wayne County - Route 31 Bridge Replacement, 312 (Box 8)
  - Waste Management, Box 8; 3.16
    Clippings, reports, and studies concerning waste management and dumping
    - Clippings, 313 (Box 8)
    - Clippings (large), 314 (Box 8)
    - Central Treatment Facility Structural Drawings, 315 (Box 8)
    - Chemical Analysis - Three Industrial Waste Samples, 316 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 317 (Box 8)
    - Drawing List for Treatment Facilities, 318 (Box 8)
    - Engineering Compliance Report, 319 (Box 8)
    - Engineering Report - Emissions Control Section, 320 (Box 8)
    - Engineering Report - Emissions Control Section Appendix A-F, 321 (Box 8)
    - Hazardous Waste Regulatory Fee Information Form 1994, 322 (Box 8)
    - Notices, 323 (Box 8)
    - Plans to Fabricate and Deliver One Chemical Wastewater Barge, 324 (Box 8)
    - Plans to Furnish and Deliver Two... Sub Pumps..., 325 (Box 8)
    - Pollution of the Interstate Waters - Summary of Conference, 326 (Box 8)
    - Preliminary Criteria for Design of a Central Pond Treatment Center, 327 (Box 8)
    - Report on Boiler Fireside and Air Preheater Wash Waste Effluents from the Waterside Generating Station..., 328 (Box 8)
    - Solid Waste Disposal, 329 (Box 8)
    - Statement to Town Board Poughkeepsie RE: Permit Application, 330 (Box 8)
- 4. Scientific Studies, 4; 5 linear feet 9 - 13 331 - 497
  Studies conducted in and around the Hudson Valley and the Hudson River.
  - Scientific Studies, Box 9; 4
    Scientific Studies A-E
    - 1974 - Axial Trawl Comb CPUE Day Only, 331 (Box 9)
    - 1974 - Beach Seine, 332 (Box 9)
    - 1974 - Fall Shoaw Survey, 333 (Box 9)
    - 1974 - Strata Densities, 334 (Box 9)